### **NABEEL HASAN**

New Delhi, India | +91-9634410235 | nabeel.io@outlook.com

Github | Linkedin | Projects

4+ years experience as a Data Analyst and Developer. I am looking forward to applying my skills in the Data Science/ML field. Swift in communication and loves to collaborate. Have experience in data pipeline and structured data analysis

### **EXPERIENCE**

# adsify.digital, Data Analyst

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

- Implemented **dashboards** in **PowerBI** to visualize and track seller KPIs and report the management in case any significant anomaly is detected.
- Generate daily reports by implementing **MySQL** scripts for Seller Listing, Shipment Fee, Ads spending, Finance unit metrics, etc. And analyze the data to gather actionable insights.
- Automated the process of generating in-depth reports using **Python** to track the seller campaigns advertising attributes based on ASIN and sponsorship type.

## adsify.digital, Python Developer

APR 2020 - OCT 2021

- Deployed Data Warehouse using **AWS RDS** to gather and store daily reports and metrics from sellers using Amazon **REST** based **SellingPartner-API** and **Ads API**.
- Implemented **ETL** pipeline in **AWS EC2** using Python **asyncio** & **httpx** to request reports of multiple sellers and transform raw data into a structured format, resulting in an 80% file size reduction
- Developed a company-wide web portal using Flask and AWS S3 for generating campaigns, seller audits, and scraping search results from Amazon and deployed the application using AWS Beanstalk.

## **IHS-Markit** Operation Analysis Analyst

AUG 2018 - JAN 2019

- **Predict** the price of illiquid securities using fixed-income data and keep track of price fluctuations.
- Maintaining the health of yield curves for GSIBs (Global Systemically Important Banks) and monitoring daily market changes.
- Keep the yield curves consistent with market changes using various **data cleaning** and filtering techniques.

#### **SKILLS**

Python, PowerBI, Exploratory Data Analysis, Statistical Analysis, Predictive Modelling, Regression Analysis, Machine Learning, A/B Testing, Web Framework, APIs, MySQL, Data Management, Data Warehousing, Linux, ETL Pipeline and Version Control.

### **EDUCATION**

MBA (Finance) Jamia Millia Islamia

AUG 2016 - APR 2018

Relevant Coursework: Risk Modeling, Financial Markets, Quantitative Analysis, Macro-Economics, Brand Marketing

BSc (Computer Application)

Aligarh Muslim University

AUG 2012 - APR 2015

**Relevant Coursework**: Programming, Object Oriented Programming, Database Management Systems, Introductory Statistics, and Probability.

### CERTIFICATION

Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Google 2023

Database Engineer Professional Certificate, Meta 2023 (Ongoing)